Finding Aid for Wilfred B. Shaw Papers 1873-1954
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Wilfred B. Shaw Papers 1873-1954, 1900-1951
Shaw, Wilfred B., 1880-1959.
1 oversize folders
7 linear feet (in 12 boxes)
General secretary of the Alumni Association of the University of Michigan and editor of the Michigan Alumnus; correspondence, drawings and etchings, photographs and other visual materials
8632 Aa 2 Ac
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was given to the library in many accessions beginning in 1936 and continuing to 1959. Donor no. 1027.
The collection is open for research.
Wilfred B. Shaw was born January 10, 1880 in Adrian, Michigan. After graduating from the University of Michigan in 1904, Shaw was named general secretary of the Alumni Association and editor of the Michigan Alumnus. He served in this capacity until 1929 when he was appointed director of alumni relations, a position that had been established by the Regents for continuing education and other services to graduates. He retired from this position in 1951. In 1934, Shaw founded and served as first editor of the Michigan Alumnus Quarterly Review.
Before coming to the University to head up its alumni relations program, Shaw had attended the Art School at Chicago. Shaw achieved some renown as an artist and etcher, particularly of U-M campus scenes, buildings, and personalities. He had many exhibitions of his work and his illustrations were used in the University's alumni publications and in his various other writings.
Shaw died May 28, 1959.
The Shaw collection is an assemblage of personal materials such as correspondence, essays and student notebook, and of Shaw's work as an artists including drawings, etchings, and other examples of artistic expression that he used in connection with his work with the University's Alumni Association and its publications. Records of Shaw's activities with the university will be found in the record groups for the Alumni Association and the Bureau of Alumni Relations also located at the Bentley Library. The collection has been divided into five series: Correspondence, Essays, Drawings and Etchings, Miscellaneous, and Photographs and other Visual Materials.
Subjects:
Adams, Henry Carter, 1851-1921.; Adrian (Mich.); Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Art.; Artists.; Hudson, Richard, 1845-1915.; Michigan alumnus quarterly review.; Michigan Union.; Scott, Fred Newton, 1860-1931.; Shaw, Wilfred Byron, 1881-1959.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan. Alumni Association.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan. Bureau of Alumni Relations.; University of Michigan. Dept. of English Language and Literature.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Political Science.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Adrian (Mich.); Adrian (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Adrian (Mich.)--Schools.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Buildings.; Alpha Delta Phi. Peninsular Chapter (University of Michigan); Apostles Club (University of Michigan); Baird, Charles, 1870-1944.; Barbour Gymnasium (University of Michigan); Boats.; Buildings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Churches.; Collegiate Sorosis (University of Michigan); Comedy Club (University of Michigan); Delta Upsilon Fraternity. University of Michigan Chapter.; Dwellings--Michigan--Adrian.; Football.; Fraternities and sororities.; Gamma Phi Beta. Beta Chapter (University of Michigan); Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Lombard, Warren P. (Warren Plimpton), 1855-1939.; Michigan Union.; Music ensembles.; Novy, Frederick George, 1864-1957.; Parades and processions.; Phi Kappa Psi. Michigan Alpha Chapter (University of Michigan); Printmaking.; Quadrangle Club (University of Michigan); Schools--Michigan--Adrian.; Shaw, Horatio Watson, 1822-1910.; Shaw, Wilfred Byron, 1881-1959.; Shaw family.; Southern Club (University of Michigan); University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan--Campus.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Football.; University of Michigan. Junior Hop.; University of Michigan. Men's Glee Club.; University of Michigan. Orchestra.; University of Michigan--Presidents.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1901-1910.; University of Michigan--Student housing--1901-1910.; University of Michigan--Sports.; University of Michigan--Track.; Western Club (University of Michigan); Wrinkle.; Greek letter societies--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; Women college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Contributors:
Babst, Earl D., 1870-1967.; Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.; Morrill, J. L. (James Lewis), 1891-1979; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Shaw, Horatio Watson, 1847-1918.; Smith, Harold J.; Stone, Ralph, 1868-1956.; Sullivan, Mark, 1874-1952.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Genre/Form:
Caricatures.; Daguerreotypes.; Drawings.; Photographs.; Prints.; Scrapbooks.
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series is arranged either by date or by topic and concerns personal activities, such as civic and non-University organizational involvement.
  - By date
    - 1904-1950, 12 folders (Box 1)
  - By topic
    - Ann Arbor 1936-1937 (Box 1)
    - Babst, Earl D. 1942-1950 (Box 1)
    - Delta Upsilon Fraternity 1931-1949 (Box 1)
    - Etchings, relating to 1928-1950 (Box 1)
    - Four Thirteen Club 1929-1941 (Box 1)
    - Frank Holmes Memorial Group 1944-1948 (Box 1)
    - Freer, Charles L. 1910-1914 (Box 1)
    - Johnson, Martyn 1904-1953 (Box 1)
    - Osborn, Chase S. 1935-1945 (Box 1)
    - Retirement 1950-1953 (Box 1)
    - Smith, Delos G. 1945-1948 (Box 1)
    - Sullivan, Mark 1922-1925 (Box 1)
    - University of Michigan Alumni Association 1873, 1902-1929 (Box 1)
      include scattered papers of earlier directors of the Association
    - University of Michigan Encyclopedic Survey, 1939-1948 (Box 1)
    - War service 1918-1919 (Box 1)
- Essays
  The Essays series consists of writings on the topic of education, art, and the history of the Michigan Union.
  - Art, illustration, etching, etc (Box 1)
  - Education (Box 1)
  - re Michigan Union 1944 (Box 1)
  - Various topics (Box 1)
- Drawings and etchings
  The largest series - Drawings and Etchings - contains illustrations done primarily to accompany articles written for the university's alumni publications and Shaw's own historical and other publications. The drawings are arranged by topic, by place name, by name of individual, by date of issue of the Michigan Alumnus Quarterly Review in which an illustration appeared, by name of University of Michigan building or view, and miscellaneous.
  - By topic
    - Farm scenes (Box 1)
    - Ships (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous subjects, 5 folders (Box 2)
      [See also oversize box 11]
  - By place names
    - Abyssinia (Box 2)
    - Alaska (Box 2)
    - Ann Arbor (Box 2)
    - Asia (Box 2)
    - Bali (Box 2)
    - Belgian Congo (Box 2)
    - Belgium (Box 2)
    - Bolivia (Box 2)
    - Brazil (Box 2)
    - Canada (Box 2)
    - Ceylon (Box 2)
    - Chile (Box 2)
    - China, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Colombia (Box 2)
    - Costa Rica (Box 2)
    - Ecuador (Box 2)
    - Egypt (Box 2)
    - England (Box 2)
    - France (Box 2)
    - Guatemala (Box 2)
    - India (Box 2)
    - Iran (Box 2)
    - Iraq (Box 2)
    - Ireland (Box 2)
    - Italy (Box 2)
    - Japan (Box 2)
    - Korea (Box 2)
    - Mexico (Box 2)
    - Michigan
      - Churches (Box 2)
      - Historic buildings (Box 2)
      - Landscapes (Box 2)
    - New Zealand (Box 2)
    - Ohio (Box 2)
    - Pacific Islands, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Peru (Box 2)
    - Philippines (Box 2)
    - Puerto Rico (Box 2)
    - Russia (Box 2)
    - Spain (Box 2)
    - Tibet (Box 2)
    - Washington, D. C (Box 2)
    - Yugoslavia (Box 2)
  - Portraits of individuals, 19 folders
    (arranged in folders by groupings of letters of the alphabet)
    - Adams, J. Donald (Box 2)
    - Adams, John (Box 2)
    - Adams, John Quincy (Box 2)
    - Ade, George (Box 2)
    - Agha, Sarkesh Wari (Box 2)
    - Alexander I, Czar of Russia (Box 2)
    - Alger, Russell A (Box 2)
    - Allen, John (Box 2)
    - Angell, James B. (Box 2)
    - Angell, James Rowland (Box 2)
    - Angell, Sarah Caswell (Box 2)
    - Arnold, Matthew (Box 2)
    - Azzchierii, Dr. Aikadi Mohammed (Box 2)
    - Bacher, Robert F (Box 2)
    - Bader, Arno (Box 2)
    - Baird, Charles (Box 2)
    - Baker, Ray Stannard (Box 2)
    - Barbour, Levi L (Box 2)
    - Bartelme, Philip George (Box 2)
    - Barton, Clara (Box 2)
    - Basu, Easil (Box 2)
    - Bates, Henry M. (Box 2)
    - Baumeister, Will (Box 2)
    - Bayes, Nora (Box 2)
    - Bentham, Jeremy (Box 2)
    - Bergson, Henri (Box 2)
    - Blanco, Gen. Ramon (Box 2)
    - Blum, Leon (Box 2)
    - Bolks, Seine (Box 2)
    - Borden, Sir Robert (Box 2)
    - Browne, Sir Thomas (Box 2)
    - Browning, Robert (Box 2)
    - Brush, Charles F (Box 2)
    - Buell, Don Carlos (Box 2)
    - Burr, Aaron (Box 2)
    - Burt, William, Austin (Box 2)
    - Burton, Marion LeRoy (Box 2)
      [See also oversize box 12]
    - Byers, Abraham S (Box 2)
    - Campbell, James V (Box 3)
    - Cantor, Eddie (Box 3)
    - Carr, John Dickson (Box 3)
    - Carrol, Wallace (Box 3)
    - Christiancy, Isaac P (Box 3)
    - Cinquez (Box 3)
    - Ciardi, John (Box 3)
    - Clarke, James Freeman (Box 3)
    - Clark, John Maurice (Box 3)
    - Clemens, Samuel (Mark Twain) (Box 3)
    - Collins, Judson Dwight (Box 3)
    - Colclazer, Rev. Henry (Box 3)
    - Conant, James B (Box 3)
    - Cooley, Thomas M (Box 3)
    - Cooper, James Fenimore (Box 3)
    - Cooper, Harry (Railroad Jack) (Box 3)
    - Cousins, Norman (Box 3)
    - Cowley, Malcolm (Box 3)
    - Crisler, Herbert O (Box 3)
    - Custer, Gen. George A (Box 3)
    - De Gaulle, Charles (Box 3)
    - Dietz, Leslie (Box 3)
    - Delafield, Major Joseph (Box 3)
    - Dewey, John (Box 3)
    - Dewey, Thomas E (Box 3)
    - Dickens, Charles (Box 3)
    - Dodds, Harold W (Box 3)
    - Douglass, Dr. Silas H (Box 3)
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo (Box 3)
    - Erasmus (Box 3)
    - Faulkner, William (Box 3)
    - Field, Stephen J (Box 3)
    - Foote, Albert E (Box 3)
    - Fox, Perrin V (Box 3)
    - Freeman (Alice Freeman Palmer) (Box 3)
    - Frieze, Henry Simmons (Box 3)
    - Frost, Robert (Box 3)
    - Fuller, Margaret (Box 3)
    - Gassner, John (Box 3)
    - Gayley, Charles M (Box 3)
    - Gibbon, Edward (Box 3)
    - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von (Box 3)
    - Graves, Benjamin Franklin (Box 3)
    - Greeley, Horace (Box 3)
    - Greene, Nathanael (Box 3)
    - Gregory, Horace (Box 3)
    - Hall, James (Box 3)
    - Hall, Louis P. (caricature) (Box 5)
    - Hamilton, Alice (Box 3)
    - Hatcher, Harlan (Box 3)
    - Haven, Erastus Otis (Box 3)
    - Hayden, Joseph R. (Box 3)
      [See oversize box 11]
    - Hemingway, Ernest (Box 3)
    - Heredia (Box 3)
    - Hinsdale, Wilbert Bartlett (Box 3)
    - Hobbs, William Herbert (Box 3)
      [see also Box 5 for caricature]
    - Hopper, DeWolf (Box 3)
    - Houghton, Douglass (Box 3)
    - Howard, William Alanson (Box 3)
    - Hutchins, Harry Burns (Box 3)
    - Innes, William P (Box 3)
    - Jefferson, Joseph (Box 3)
    - Jefferson, Thomas (Box 3)
    - Johnson, Andrew (Box 3)
    - Johnston, Clarence (Box 3)
      [see Box 5 for caricature]
    - Jones, Howard Mumford (Box 3)
    - Jones, Sir William (Box 3)
    - Jungkenn, General von (Box 3)
    - Kearsley, Jonathan (Box 3)
    - Kenyon, H.A. (Box 3)
    - Khan, Begum Liaquat Ali (Box 3)
    - Kuhn, Sherman M (Box 3)
    - Kurath, Hans (Box 3)
    - Lamarck, Jean Baptiste (Box 3)
    - Laurier, Wilfred (Box 3)
    - Lee, Fitz-Hugh (Box 3)
    - L'Enfant, Charles Pierre (Box 3)
    - Little, Clarence Cook (Box 3)
    - Lloyd, Alfred H. (Box 3)
    - Locke, John (Box 3)
    - Lopez, Aaron (Box 3)
    - Lyon, Lucius (Box 3)
    - Macauley, Thomas Babington (Box 3)
    - MacIver, Robert Morrison (Box 3)
    - Mann, Thomas (Box 3)
    - Markley, Joseph (Box 3)
    - Marquis, Don (Box 3)
    - Marshall, John (Box 3)
    - Martin, George (Box 3)
    - Mason, Stevens T. (Box 3)
    - Mayo, William J (Box 3)
    - McCreery, William B. (Box 3)
    - McLaughlin, Andrew (Box 3)
    - McLeish, Archibald (Box 3)
    - McLenan, Danny (Box 3)
    - McMath, Robert R (Box 3)
    - Milligan, L.P (Box 3)
    - Mills, Walter Thomas (Box 3)
    - Molitor, Albert (Box 3)
    - Montesquieu, Baron Charles Louis (Box 3)
    - Montressor, John (Box 3)
    - Morris, William (Box 3)
    - Mosher, Eliza B. (Box 3)
    - Nietzsche, Friedrich (Box 3)
    - Nye, William (Box 3)
    - O'Casey, Sean (Box 3)
    - O'Neill, Eugene (Box 3)
    - O'Neill, James (Box 3)
    - Osborn, Chase S (Box 3)
    - Paderewski, Ignace Jan (Box 3)
    - Pandit, Vijaya Lakshmi (Box 3)
    - Parke, Hervey C (Box 3)
    - Pattengill, Albert H. (Box 3)
    - Patterson, Harold (Box 3)
    - Perry, Ralph Barton (Box 3)
    - Piatigorski, Gregor (Box 3)
    - Pierce, John D (Box 3)
    - Pingree, Hazen (Box 3)
    - Pitcher, Zina (Box 3)
    - Pope, Col. Albert A (Box 3)
    - Pound, Edward Harold (Box 3)
    - Pritchard, Benjamin Dudley (Box 3)
    - Rahv, Philip (Box 3)
    - Rajam, Sunalini Deva (Box 3)
    - Randall, John Henry (Box 3)
    - Rhee, Syngman (Box 3)
    - Richard, Gabriel (Box 3)
    - Richelieu, Le Duc de (Box 3)
    - Robbins, F.E. (Box 3)
      [See box 5 for caricature]
    - Rogers, Randolph (Box 3)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 3)
    - Roth, Filibert (Box 3)
    - Ruthven, Alexander Grant (Box 3)
    - Sager, Abram (Box 3)
    - Salmon, Lucy Maynard (Box 3)
    - Santayana, George (Box 3)
    - Sanders, Henry A (Box 3)
    - Sarmiento, D.F (Box 3)
    - Schoolcraft, Henry (Box 3)
    - Scott, F.N (Box 3)
    - Shumann-Heink (Box 3)
    - Simoneau, Jules (Box 3)
    - Shearer, James (Box 3)
    - Shelburne, Lord (Box 3)
    - Sheridan, Philip H (Box 3)
    - Sherry, George (Box 3)
    - Sigsbee, Charles D (Box 3)
    - Singh, Surgit (Box 3)
    - Sorel, Georges (Box 3)
    - Spender, Stephen (Box 3)
    - Spinoza, Benedict (Box 3)
    - Stanley, Albert Augustus (Box 3)
    - Stevenson, Adlai (Box 3)
    - Stiles, Ezra (Box 3)
    - Stokes, Thomas L (Box 3)
    - Strauss, Louis A. (Box 3)
    - Streseman, Gustav (Box 3)
    - Stuart, Mary (Box 3)
    - Swinburne, Algernon Charles (Box 3)
    - Tappan, Henry P. (Box 3)
    - Taylor, Annie Edson (Box 3)
    - Ten Brook, Andrew (Box 3)
    - Tennyson, Alfred Lord (Box 3)
    - Thackery, William Makepeace (Box 3)
    - Thomas, George Henry (Box 3)
    - Tiffin, Edward (Box 3)
    - Trollope, Anthony (Box 3)
    - Turk, Thomas (Box 3)
    - Turk, Mrs. Thomas (Box 3)
    - Tyler, Moses Coit (Box 3)
    - Vandenberg, Senator Arthur (Box 3)
    - Van Doren, Mark (Box 3)
    - Van Raalte, Albertus C (Box 3)
    - Van Tyne, C.H. (Box 3)
    - Vargas, Getulio (Box 3)
    - Vaughan, Victor C (Box 3)
    - Walker, Edward C (Box 3)
    - Ward, David (Box 3)
    - Warren, Earl (Box 3)
    - Warren, Robert Penn (Box 3)
    - Washington, George (Box 3)
    - Watson, James C (Box 3)
    - Weld, Theodore D (Box 3)
    - Wheeler, Henry Mason (Box 3)
    - White, Andrew D (Box 3)
    - Whitman, Walt (Box 3)
    - Wilson, Woodrow (Box 3)
    - Whitney, J.D (Box 3)
    - Willard, George (Box 3)
    - Winter, John A (Box 3)
    - Wisner, Moses (Box 3)
    - Woodhead, Arthur E (Box 3)
    - Woodhedge, William (Box 3)
    - Wright, Carolyn Day (Box 3)
    - Wright, Charles E (Box 3)
    - Wright, Charles Will (Box 3)
    - Wright, Clarence A (Box 3)
    - Wright, Fredrick Eugene (Box 3)
    - Wu, Yi-Fang (Box 3)
    - Yeats, William Butler (Box 3)
    - Yost, Fielding H (Box 3)
  - Arranged by date of issue of the Michigan Alumnus Quarterly Review in which drawings appeared
    - 1935-1959, 35 folders (Box 3)
  - University of Michigan buildings and views
    - Alumnae House 1942 (Box 9)
    - Alumni Memorial Hall (Box 9)
    - Angell Hall in 1925 (Box 9)
    - Campus view
      - Mall (Box 9)
      - University in 1850 from the East (Box 9)
    - Campus view featuring Hill Auditorium, Burton Tower, and proposed music school (Box 9)
    - East Quadrangle (Box 9)
    - Ferry Field and Ann Arbor skyline (Box 9)
    - Hospital. Old Hospital on Catherine Street (Box 9)
    - Hospital. First University Hospital (Box 9)
    - Kellogg Building and Health Service (Box 9)
    - Lawyers Club (Box 9)
    - McMath-Hulbert Observatory (Box 9)
    - Michigan League (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
    - Natural History Museum (Box 9)
    - Old Medical Building (Box 9)
    - Presidents House (Box 9)
    - Rackham Building, 2 images (Box 9)
    - Residences. Women's Halls, 2 images (Box 9)
    - Two first University buildings rendered in 1938 (Box 9)
    - University Hall (Box 9)
    - University Library (Box 9)
    - Unknown (Box 9)
    - West Quadrangle (Box 9)
    - West Quadrangle lounge February 1942 (Box 9)
    - William Clements Library (Box 9)
  - University of Michigan Illustrated
    (etching series of University buildings, views and presidents)
    (this subseries includes multiple copies of signed and unsigned prints)
    - Angell Hall, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Alumni Memorial Hall (Box 10)
    - Center of the campus (Box 10)
    - Clements Library (Box 10)
    - Delta Upsilon House (Box 10)
    - Engineering Quadrangle (Box 10)
    - Lawyers Club Quadrangle (Box 10)
    - Law Quadrangle (Box 10)
    - Martha Cook Building doorway (Box 10)
    - Michigan Creed, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Michigan League (Box 10)
    - Michigan Stadium (Box 10)
    - Michigan Union, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Old University Hall (Box 10)
    - President's House (Box 10)
    - President's House (digitally reproduced from original) (Box 10)
    - President's House from the Lawyers Club (Box 10)
    - Presidents portraits (Box 10)
      (5 framed portraits in basement storage)
    - Rackham Building (Box 10)
    - University of Michigan Hospital, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Gothic chapel (proposed first University of Michigan building to be done by Alexander Davis) (Box 11)
    - Ann Arbor [includes Frederick Novy house] (Box 11)
    - Portraits, 3 folders (Box 11)
      (contents listed in portraits subseries)
    - Illustrations used in Wrinkle publication, 1902-1904 (Box 11)
      (stored in oversize folder Ac)
    - Monhegan Harbor, Maine (watercolor from etching) (Box 11)
      (framed, in basement art collection)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Box 11)
    - Early sketches and a letter from John T. McCutchens (Box 4)
    - Drawings by H. Wood of the Detroit News (Box 4)
    - Scrapbooks of clippings of Shaw drawings used in the Michigan Alumnus Quarterly Review, 4 volumes (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous
  Miscellaneous is an arbitrary grouping of such items as Shaw's notes as a student at the University of Michigan, copies of letters of artist and family member, Horatio Shaw, and a collection of Christmas and greeting cards.
  - Student notebooks 1901, 2 volumes (Box 5)
  - re Horatio W. Shaw 1878-1947 (include typescripts of letters) (Box 5)
  - Postcards (Box 5)
  - Christmas cards (Box 5)
- Photographs and other visual materials
  Photographs and other Visual Materials includes family photographs, an album and foldered photographs from the period when Shaw was a U-M student. Included are glass negatives for which copy prints have been made and glass slides of caricatures of university personalities. The photographs are of the Brackley and Byron Shaw families and their life in Adrian, Michigan. There are also photographs of various University of Michigan sororities and fraternities, and University of Michigan athletes, coaches and sporting events.
  - Portraits
    - Brackley Shaw family portraits (Box 5)
    - Horatio W. Shaw (Box 5)
      [See also daguerreotypes stored with UAx photos]
    - Wilfred B. Shaw Portraits (including photos of Shaw and Warren P. Lombard printing etchings) (Box 5)
  - Copy prints from glass negatives, 4 envelopes
    (negatives stored in Box 7)
    - My First Room in Delta Upsilon House with Bob (Box 5)
      (print no. 1)
    - Old Delta Upsilon House, Exterior (Box 5)
      (print no. 2)
    - Old Delta Upsilon House, Interior (Box 5)
      (print no. 3)
    - Old Delta Upsilon House, Interior with piano (Box 5)
      (print no. 4)
    - Dining Room [Delta Upsilon House?], 3 prints (Box 5)
      (prints no. 5-7)
    - Our room at Heir Ardres' (?) (Box 5)
      (print no. 8)
    - Our room at Cliff Roe's (?) (Box 5)
      (print no. 9)
    - Mrs. Hart's room, 3 prints (Box 5)
      (prints no. 10-12)
    - Esther and Charlotte's room (Box 5)
      (print no. 13)
    - Mrs. D's room, 3 prints (Box 5)
      (prints no. 14-16)
    - Leon and (?) room, 2 prints (Box 5)
      (prints no. 17-18)
    - Sitting room (Box 5)
      (print no. 19)
    - Bertha Shaw's old room (Box 5)
      (print no. 20)
    - Miss Mary Neals and Bertha Shaw (Box 5)
      (print no. 21)
    - Miss Corbin's (?) house (Box 5)
      (print no. 22)
    - Unidentified student room (Box 5)
      (print no. 23)
    - Unidentified Women's room (Box 5)
      (prints no. 24)
    - Campus and Library, 2 prints (Box 5)
      (prints no. 25-26)
    - University Hall, 2 prints (Box 5)
      (prints no. 27-28)
    - Library, interior (Box 5)
      (print no. 29)
    - Library, interior with people (Box 5)
      (prints no. 30)
    - Old soldiers (Civil War?)-parade in Adrian, Michigan; Dated April 26th (believed to be 1900--the 35th Anniversary of the end of the Civil War) (Box 5)
      (print no. 31)
    - Band and Templars-parade in Adrian, Michigan; Dated April 4th (believed to be 1900--the 35th Anniversary of the end of the Civil War) (Box 5)
      (print no. 32)
    - County Fair, Ann Arbor (Box 5)
      (print no. 33)
    - Line-up, Tecumseh-Adrian football game, c. 1899 (Box 5)
      (print no. 34)
    - High School Museum (Adrian High School?) (Box 5)
      (print no. 35)
    - The river at Picnic Bend (Box 5)
      (prints no. 36)
    - Jans Strorige (?), on the boulevard (Box 5)
      (print no. 37)
    - "The Woods", winter 1900 (Box 5)
      (print no. 38)
    - Florence W. and Bob Lee's girl, J Hop 1900 (Box 5)
      (prints no. 39)
    - Unidentified group, with sign (Box 5)
      (print no. 40)
    - Unidentified woman in horse-drawn carriage (Box 5)
      (print no. 41)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Shaw home in Adrian, Adrian High School class photos, and Apostles Club and Wrinkle staff (Box 5)
      [See also 3 folders in oversize box 12]
  - Caricatures (lantern slides) of University of Michigan faculty members, 1 boxes
    - Hall, Louis P (Box 5)
    - Hobbs, William Herbert (Box 5)
    - Johnston, Clarence (Box 5)
    - Kenyon, H.A (Box 5)
    - Lloyd, Alfred H (Box 5)
    - Markley, Joseph (Box 5)
    - Robbins, F.E (Box 5)
    - Strauss, Louis A (Box 5)
    - Van Tyne, C.H (Box 5)
  - Photograph Albums
    - Byron L. Shaw family album 1874-circa 1900, 1 volumes (Box 5)
    - Album of University of Michigan student activities, disbound circa 1900-1904
      - Buildings and Faculty (including cornerstone-laying and dedication of New Medical (now Natural Resources) Building) (Box 8)
      - Athletics-Men circa 1900-1905
        - Charles Baird portraits (Box 8)
        - Football (Box 8)
        - Track (Box 8)
        - Baseball, Gymnastics, Golf, and Fencing (Box 8)
      - Athletics-Women circa 1900-1905
        (mainly at Barbour Gymnasium)
        - Women's basketball (Box 8)
        - Women's fencing (Box 8)
        - Women's gymnastics ("Swedish Exercises") (Box 8)
      - Fraternities and sororities
        - Alpha Delta Phi (Box 8)
        - Alpha Phi (Box 8)
        - Beta Theta Pi (Box 8)
        - Chi Psi (Box 8)
        - Collegiate Sorosis (Box 8)